So, this is the first lecture over Python course.
So, you can say Python course.
We will see in this video introduction to Python, right?
You can say some features of this language application areas who are using this Python.
Why this is so popular nowadays on features?
This kind of theme we will be discussing in this video about Python or Python.
I will pronounce it as Python, right?
Okay, now see, Python is nowadays the most popular programming language.
But you can say it is the fastest growing programming language nowadays.
It's not like that it is new language because you you know you think that recently it is it has become so popular.
So, it is a new language.
No, the concept of Python came into picture in 1989 and even Java was you know the concept of Java came into picture in 1995.
So, it is before Java, right?
But recently in past few years like Python has become so much popular and why so that also we will discuss, right?
Now, basically in every area Python is being used right now.
The main areas are machine learning data science artificial intelligence.
See nowadays the data is a big problem.
Many companies like you can say your Facebook, YouTube, any shopping websites.
They are having data of billions of users, right?
And how they manage that data and one more thing is what?
See, I think you have noticed if you suppose nowadays I you know, a search for especially chicken curry kurtas, right?
So, I have I've been looking for these kurtas on two or three websites, shopping websites and whenever I open any other website, you know, for study, that kind of thing.
So, those relevant ads they show me, right?
Ads of those chicken curry kurtas and all.
So, how they come to know that advertisers like how they come to know?